Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Utility Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning utility companies operating in the North American West
1902-1961
Ndy51
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.14
(15 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning utility companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, company descriptions, newspaper clippings, press releases, prospectuses, reports, maps, stock and bond offerings, plans for exchange of securities, notices and letters to the stockholders, dividend notices, deposit agreements, certificates of deposit, trust and mortgage indentures, trust agreements, agreements of assignment and pledge, bankruptcy notices to creditors, plans of reorganization and court documents. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning utility companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, company descriptions, newspaper clippings, press releases, prospectuses, reports, maps, stock and bond offerings, plans for exchange of securities, notices and letters to the stockholders, dividend notices, deposit agreements, certificates of deposit, trust and mortgage indentures, trust agreements, agreements of assignment and pledge, bankruptcy notices to creditors, plans of reorganization and court documents. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Public utilities -- West (U.S.); Trust indentures -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- American Power and Light Company, 1911-1949; Ndy51 U2 +Am4; (42 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- American Public Service Company, 1912-1926; Ndy51 U2 +Am5; (5 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Utilities Company, 1912-1926; Ndy51 U2 +Am7; (6 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Central Power and Light Company, 1922-1940; Ndy51 U2 +C34; (17 documents) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Central States Power and Light Corporation, 1928; Ndy51 U2 +C352; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Central West Public Service Company, 1926-1941; Ndy51 U2 +C37; (10 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Cities Service Power and Light Company, 1924-1943; Ndy51 U2 +C5; (11 documents) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- Community Power and Light Company, 1923-1942; Ndy51 U2 +C75; (9 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Dallas Electric Corporation, 1902-1917; Ndy51 U2 +D15; (4 documents) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Dallas Electric Company, 1913-1923; Ndy51 U2 +D16; (12 documents) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Eastern Texas Electric Company, 1911-1926; Ndy51 U2 +Ea77; (33 documents) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- General Public Utilities Company, 1926; Ndy51 U2 +G28; (3 documents) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Gulf Public Service Company, 1925; Ndy51 U2 +G95; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Gulf States Utilities Company, 1926-1938; Ndy51 U2 +G96; (5 documents) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Inland Power and Light Corporation, 1926-1927; Ndy51 U2 +In5; (5 documents) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- International Utilities Corporation, 1925-1930; Ndy51 U2 +In6; (3 documents) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Interstate Electric Corporation, 1913-1927; Ndy51 U2 +In7; (10 documents) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Iowa Southern Utilities Company, 1923-1935; Ndy51 U2 +Io8; (7 documents) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Lake Charles Electric Company, 1924; Ndy51 U2 +L14; (3 documents) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Lincoln Public Service Company, 1926; Ndy51 U2 +L63; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Louisiana Ice and Electric Company, 1936-1946; Ndy51 U2 +L92
  Scope and Contents
  Included are documents from the Central Louisiana Electric Company.
  - Financial history, 1936-1946; (7 documents) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Economic aspects, 1945; (1 document) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Louisiana Ice and Utilities Company, 1934; Ndy51 U2 +L93; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Missouri Power and Light Company, 1922-1925; Ndy51 U2 +M69; (8 documents) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Included are documents from the he Missouri Utilities Company.
- Mountain States Power Company, 1918-1937; Ndy51 U2 +M86; (4 documents) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Nevada-California Electric Corporation, 1916-1939; Ndy51 U2 +N41
  - Financial history, 1916-1939; (19 documents) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Economic aspects, 1928-1933; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- New Orleans Public Service Inc., 1922-1945; Ndy51 U2 +N47; (13 documents) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Northern California Company, Consolidated, 1908; Ndy51 U2 +N81; (1 document) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Northern States Power Company (of Delaware), 1912-1938; Ndy51 U2 +N83; (20 documents) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  Included are documents from the Consumers Power Company of Minnesota.
- Northern States Power Company (Minnesota), 1916-1937; Ndy51 U2 +N835; (54 documents) (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
- Northwestern Public Service Company, 1923; Ndy51 U2 +N85; (1 document) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Oklahoma Power and Water Company, 1928; Ndy51 U2 +Ok4; (1 document) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Pacific Power and Light Company, 1910-1946; Ndy51 U2 +P12; (42 documents) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Peoples Light and Power Corporation, 1926-1936; Ndy51 U2 +P39; (17 documents) (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- Public Service Company of Colorado, 1923-1950; Ndy51 U2 +P92; (13 documents) (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
- Public Service Company of Oklahoma, 1922-1936; Ndy51 U2 +P925; (10 documents) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Public Utilities Consolidated Corporation, 1928; Ndy51 U2 +P952; (2 documents) (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Puget Sound Power and Light Company, 1920-1943; Ndy51 U2 +P96; (46 documents) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- Puget Sound Traction, Light & Power Company, 1911-1920; Ndy51 U2 +P963; (28 documents) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Southwestern Public Service Company, 1922-1961; Ndy51 U2 +R71; (4 documents) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Included are documents from the Roswell Public Service Company.
- St. Joseph Railway, Light, Heat & Power Company, 1902-1937; Ndy51 U2 +Sa2; (6 documents) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- San Antonio Public Service Company, 1917-1938; Ndy51 U2 +Sa5; (7 documents) (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
- Sierra Pacific Electric Company, 1910-1937; Ndy51 U2 +Si2; (9 documents) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Sioux City Gas and Electric Company, 1922-1936; Ndy51 U2 +Si7; (7 documents) (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Southwestern Gas and Electric Company, 1912-1935; Ndy51 U2 +So6; (11 documents) (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Southwestern Light and Power Company, 1925-1927; Ndy51 U2 +So65; (5 documents) (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Southwestern Power and Light Company, 1913-1924; Ndy51 U2 +So7; (18 documents) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
- Southwestern Utilities Corporation, 1923; Ndy51 U2 +So8; (3 documents) (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Standard Gas and Electric Company, 1911-1941; Ndy51 U2 +St2
  - Financial history, 1911-1941; (47 documents) (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Economic aspects, 1916-1930; (6 documents) (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Texas-Louisiana Power Company, 1926-1944; Ndy51 U2 +T31; (6 documents) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- United Power and Light Corporation (of Kansas), 1924-1927; Ndy51 U2 +Un6; (6 documents) (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Utah Securities Corporation, 1913-1925; Ndy51 U2 +Ut1; (7 documents) (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Utilities Power & Light Corporation, 1924-1930; Ndy51 U2 +Ut4; (7 documents) (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Washington-Idaho Water, Light and Power Company, 1922-1923; Ndy51 U2 +W27; (3 documents) (Box 14, Folder 5)
- West Texas Utilities Company, 1927-1939; Ndy51 U2 +W53; (3 documents) (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Western Light & Telephone Company, 1944-1951; Ndy51 U2 +W536; (5 documents) (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Western Light & Telephone Company, Inc., 1946-1949; Ndy51 U2 +W5361; (3 documents) (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Western Public Service Company, 1912-1925; Ndy51 U2 +W54; (5 documents) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Included are documents from the Intermountain Railway, Light & Power Company.
- Western States Gas and Electric Company (of California), 1910-1922; Ndy51 U2 +W55; (8 documents) (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Wisconsin-Minnesota Light and Power Company, 1918; Ndy51 U2 +W76; (1 document) (Box 15, Folder 2)